Qualifications Summary

Customer focused with a passion to proofread and copy edit as per style guide and learn emerging technologies; possess over 8 years of progressive experience in varied domains

Profile

Technically talented Proofreader and Copy Editor with excellent customer service skills; enjoy working in a fast-paced environment with challenging and complex documents; rich experience in proofreading and ensuring quality of financial documents, brochures, flyers, promotional material and retail catalogues; equipped with fast and accurate keyboarding skills, advanced word processing skills, expert in electronic tagging of legal documents in SGML and XML. An active team player recognized for taking initiatives to achieve desired business and organizational goals.

Tools

GIMP (image editor), Paint.net (image editor), HTML 5, CSS 3, Microsoft Office 2019/Office 365 (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook & Publisher), Adobe Acrobat Reader & Writer, Adobe InDesign CC, Adobe Photoshop CC, Adobe FrameMaker, Microsoft Project, Accounting Fundamentals and Lotus Notes

Professional Experience and Accomplishments

PwC Canada, Toronto, 2022 – Present

Document Proofreading Specialist

- Identify omissions and inconsistencies in financial statements and proofread for grammatical and format errors
- Check amounts and perform calculations in financial statements while cross-referencing numbers in documents and all note references
- Make suggestions for accounting terminology, general language (syntax, vocabulary) and presentation, ensure PwC formats and brand are properly applied
- Query practice staff regarding any questions that arise or suggest corrections and review suggested changes
- Work closely with engagement teams to clarify expectations, update on the progress of the work and focus on quality and timely delivery of the work

St. Joseph Communications, Content Division, North York, Toronto, 2010 – 2022 Proofreader/Quality Controller

- Proofread all pages moving through the quality checking process and ensured that page assembly operators had implemented corrections
- Checked for obvious errors and ensured that all pages adhered to style guidelines
- Compared images to related copy blocks on the printed page to ensure that they were consistent and correspond to one another
- Compared all final PDF files from the imaging department to the final corrected pages submitted from the proofreading department to ensure that they matched and no images or copy had gone missing
- Copy edited content provident by client at initial stage
- Trained new hire proofreaders

RR Donnelley & Sons (formerly Bowne of Canada), Toronto, 2010 Composition Operator and Proofreader

- Produced financial documents and included author's comments
- Adhered to Bowne style and prepared files for Xmarking to save down from PDF and/or Xlates
- Proofread output against the customers' document for style, composition, spelling accuracy and consistency
- Edited the financial documents and ensured overall consistency, style and pagination

INOFAS Integrated Systems Inc., Toronto, 2008 – 2009

Text Processing Specialist/SGML/XML Tagger

- Performed electronic tagging of documents in SGML & XML
- Proofread and reformatted legal documents created by scanning or OCR
- Identified and reported anomalies and provided appropriate solutions

TC Media (formerly Quad Graphics & Que-Net Media), Markham, 2007 – 2008 Proofreader

- Proofread retail catalogues and adhered to APA style guidelines
- Ensured consistency in the catalogue and maintained pricing, copy and design on all pages and zones.

Educational and Professional Credentials

Proofread like a Pro, 2022

Udemy

Introduction to Adobe Photoshop CC, 2019

Gale Courses/ed2go Courses, Toronto Public Library

Introduction to InDesign CC, 2018

Gale Courses/ed2go Courses, Toronto Public Library

Beginning Conversational French, 2018

Gale Courses/ed2go Courses, Toronto Public Library

Certificate in Keys to Effective Editing, 2018

Gale Courses/ed2go Courses, Toronto Public Library

Certificate in Technical Writing with Honours, 2013

Humber College, Toronto, Canada

Bachelor of Arts (English Literature), 1997

Madras University, India